<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Ankit Ahuja</title><link>https://ankitahuja.com/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Ankit Ahuja</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 23:40:54 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ankitahuja.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Notes From Dec 2021</title><link>https://ankitahuja.com/notes-from-dec-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 23:40:54 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://ankitahuja.com/notes-from-dec-2021/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="notes-from-dec-2021">Notes from Dec 2021&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Dec 2021 was the first month in my break from work. Here are some journal notes.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Thanks to New Yorker friends, I had a great time exploring food and activities. The city is fast, energetic, exhausting but full of interesting people and experiences. Some highlights -&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Learnt how to eat cheap when not cooking in New York, with a combination of delis and TJs. And rest of the time, enjoyed exceptional food.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Boardgames at The Uncommons. You really don&amp;rsquo;t need to own boardgames&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Ran 5 miles around Central Park&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Enjoyed holiday lights in the New York Botanical Garden&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Comedy at Bowery Electric and jazz at Dizzy&amp;rsquo;s Club and Terra Blues&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Reading at Book Club and other cafes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Found my favorite &lt;a href="https://www.misoyanyc.com/">ramen&lt;/a> place in the city&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Felt nostalgic about Delhi in Jackson Heights, Queens&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Read &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/54493401-project-hail-mary">Project Hail Mary&lt;/a> by Andy Weir. Really fun sci-fi book.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Started watching &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/user/Campbellteaching">Dr. John Campbell&amp;rsquo;s YouTube&lt;/a> on Omicron everday. His optimistic and scientific approach to summarizing the science and updates around Covid-19 is refreshing.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I want to live everyday with intent and mindfully. I want to read books, listen to podcasts and watch talks more mindfully. Perhaps by taking more notes and summarizing thoughts.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Taking a break from work is doing immense good to my mental health.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>It feels uneasy to move. Even more so after getting used to the pace of life in New York and building connections with friends. It&amp;rsquo;s important to stay in one place to build community.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Hence, drafted a more concrete plan for how I want to spend my break with the eventual goal to settle down in a city.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Leaving Coursera</title><link>https://ankitahuja.com/leaving-coursera/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 12:31:27 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://ankitahuja.com/leaving-coursera/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="leaving-coursera">Leaving Coursera&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ankitahuja.com/images/coursera-penguin.jpg" alt="teammate&amp;rsquo;s penguin with headphones plushie">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve departed Coursera after working there for the past 7+ years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am extremely thankful for all the personal and professional relationships I built with the people there. I will always cherish the memories, including the offsites, make-a-thons, ping pong, badminton, tennis, cricket and soccer we played during my time there. The informal and grad-school-like culture in my initial years at the company was the highlight of my time spent there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got to work towards a mission that I believe truly makes the world a better place.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="so-why-leave">So, why leave?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I would be lying if I said it was an easy decision. Change is hard, especially when you have been comfortable in your current life for the last 7 years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s hard for me to pinpoint a single reason for leaving, but there were a few reasons that contributed to it.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I was no longer enjoying work and experiencing burnout. I felt like I needed to disconnect and take a break. I can&amp;rsquo;t point to a single reason, perhaps it was working from home, company culture changing with growth or just getting tired of the same-ness. Taking vacations didn&amp;rsquo;t really help.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d been thinking about what&amp;rsquo;s next in the background for quite a while and couldn&amp;rsquo;t really figure out exactly where or what I wanted to do next. I felt like I needed to give myself space to figure that out. Sometimes, you have to make a decision to move your thinking forward.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I wanted to move out of the bay area and San Francisco. Even though I like the people, the weather and the food, I want to live in a city where there is more diversity of people and conversations beyond tech, more things to do, more walkability and excellent public transport. I felt like I needed a change.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>I could afford to take a break financially. Even though it feels overwhelming to resign and move at the same time, I am equally excited about the ambiguity ahead.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="whats-next">What&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Moving gives you a chance to practice &lt;a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/30231806-goodbye-things">minimalism&lt;/a> all over again and reduce the number of things you own. I enjoy that aspect of moving. I enjoy selling and giving away things I no longer need to people who would enjoy them. However, leaving community in your current location is uncomfortable at best.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I plan to live nomadically, read a lot, write, work on fun projects and recharge. I don&amp;rsquo;t have a concrete plan, except for the next few months (NYC then Delhi).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am writing this on my day 1 after leaving, and it already feels quite different. I feel like I have hit the reset button and have a lot of flexibility in actively deciding what&amp;rsquo;s next for me. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how this experiment turns out!&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="thanks">Thanks&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Leading up to this decision, I want to thank my family, friends and co-workers who listened to me, offered their advice and supported me. I also found inspiration in reading stories from people and learning from their perspective - &lt;a href="https://blog.matsu.io/on-leaving">Pine&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://muan.co/2020/10/02/leaving-github/">Mu-An&lt;/a>, &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/dvassallo">@dvassollo&amp;rsquo;s tweets&lt;/a>. Hence, I wanted to share my perspective in addition to writing down my thoughts for my own sake.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>